A Guide to the Louis I. Jaffé Papers, 1931-1949
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Louis I. Jaffé Papers, 1931-1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9924-k
This collection consists of ca. 430 items.
Mrs. Louis I. Jaffé
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift to the Library from Mrs. Louis I. Jaffé of Norfolk, Virginia, on November 6, 1985.
Biographical/Historical Information
There is extensive material concerning the successful efforts to incorporate Norfolk Polytechnic College into Virginia State College (Petersburg), thereby establishing a Norfolk Division of Virginia State College. An attempt was then made to locate the new Norfolk extension in the Saint Vincent's Hospital Nurses' Home which was vacated after World War II and had become city property. Proponents believed this building would be a good place for the school, especially since it was in an area that was predominantly black. As a member of the "white advisory section" of the Board of Trustees of Norfolk Polytechnic College, Jaffé was active in its development and growth.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Louis I. Jaffé Papers consists of ca. 430 items, ca. 1931-1949, containing supplementary correspondence files. Included are correspondence, reports, newspaper clippings, printed material, and photographs. There is information concerning blacks, suffrage reform, public health, military matters, Judaism, Norfolk, and other public issues.
Correspondents involved with the project include Governor Colgate Whitehead Darden, Jr., Norfolk City Manager Charles B. Borland, Lyman Beecher Brooks and G. W. C. Brown of Norfolk Polytechnic College, L. H. Foster of the Virginia State College, and Dabney Stewart Lancaster from the State Board of Education. There are also three photographs of the Saint Vincent's Nurses' Home. Other material pertaining to blacks can be found under "Southern Regional Council, Inc." including minutes of the Executive Committee and Board meetings and "Suffrage Reform" as well as general files "A," "B," "C," "D," "H," "L," "N," "V."
Arrangement
Folders are arranged in alphabetical order, and items within folders are mainly alphabetical according to topic.
Contents List
- A 1936-1940, 1962, 11 items (Box 1)
- B 1937-1949, 9 items (Box 1)
- C 1934-1944, 25 items (Box 1)
- D 1938-1947, 11 items (Box 1)
- E 1938-1944, 7 items (Box 1)
- F 1938-1947, 10 items (Box 1)
- G 1938-1949, 7 items (Box 1)
- H 1936-1947, 14 items (Box 1)
- I 1943-1944, 11 items (Box 1)
- J 1937-1944, 15 items (Box 1)
- Louis I Jaffé's edited letter 1945, 1 item (Box 1)
  Re "St. Vincent's Project"
- K 1938-1947, 6 items (Box 1)
- L 1938-1943, 8 items (Box 1)
- M 1931-1949, 27 items (Box 2)
- N 1935-1949, 18 items (Box 2)
- O 1944, 2 items (Box 2)
- P 1941-1947, 5 items (Box 2)
- R 1937-1946, 12 items (Box 2)
- S 1940-1947, 10 items (Box 2)
- Edward Streeter: Dere "Mable" 1918, 1 item, printed (Box 2)
  Love letters of a Rookie, circulated among young officers in World War I France.
- St. Vincent's Project for Negro College (under several names) and for Navy USO 1943-1944, 68 items (Box 2)
- St. Vincent's Project for Negro College (under several names) and for Navy USO 1945-1949, 60 items (Box 2)
- Southern Regional Council 1944-1949, 12 items (Box 2)
  Minutes of Board Meetings
- Southern Regional Council 1944-1949, 16 items (Box 3)
  Southern Frontier and The New South
- Southern Regional Council 1944-1949, 12 items (Box 3)
  Varied material
- Suffrage Reform 1945, 6 items (Box 3)
  Clippings
- Suffrage Reform 1945, 7 items (Box 3)
  Material relating to presentation to the Legislature
- T 1914, 1940-1943, 13 items (Box 3)
- U-V 1937-1949, 18 items (Box 3)
- W 1931-1939, 7 items (Box 3)
- X-Y-Z 1938, 1 item (Box 3)